<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>embedded sigproc</title>
    <link>https://abhipray.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on embedded sigproc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://abhipray.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On linearity: straight lines, linear operators &amp; the Fourier transform</title>
      <link>https://abhipray.com/posts/sigproc/linearity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhipray.com/posts/sigproc/linearity/</guid>
      <description>The list of engineering ideas centered on linearity is endless: linear regression, linear time-invariant (LTI) filter, linear dynamical system, linearization, support vector machines, circuit theory/network analysis etc. Most of these ideas are introduced with a cursorsy view of the significance of linearity. In this post, I want to flip the perspective and make linearity the central theme and elucidate how other ideas depend on it.
We probably all think straight line when we think of the word linear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDM-PCM conversion &amp; PDM&#39;s connection to neurons</title>
      <link>https://abhipray.com/posts/sigproc/pdm_pcm_conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhipray.com/posts/sigproc/pdm_pcm_conversion/</guid>
      <description>Background In the context of digital audio systems, PDM is a common interface between microphones and microcontrollers/signal processors. PDM signals represent analog audio signals by sampling the analog microphone waveform at a very high rate with a single bit resolution (on/off) for the amplitude. This encodes the analog signal in the density of the pulses and hence the name, Pulse Density Modulation.
For example, if you want the microphone to record an analog audio signal with a bandwidth of 24KHz (FNyquist), you sample it at say 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>